export const questionData = [
  {
    answer:
      "1.  An injury or illness must be AOE/COE to be covered by workers’ compensation.\n2. AOE / COE: que surge fuera del empleo y en el curso del empleo o es causado por el trabajo de un trabajador y ocurre mientras trabaja. Una lesión o enfermedad debe ser AOE / COE para estar cubierta por la compensación de trabajadores.",
    question:
      "What is Arising Out of Employment, and in the Course Of Employment (AOE)?",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. If you have an attorney, an AME is a doctor, your attorney and the insurance company agree to conduct the medical examination that will help resolve your dispute. If you don't have an attorney, you will use a qualified medical evaluator (QME).\n2. Evaluador médico acordado (AME): si tiene un abogado, un AME es un médico, su abogado y la compañía de seguros acuerdan realizar el examen médico que ayudará a resolver su disputa. Si no tiene un abogado, utilizará un evaluador médico calificado (QME).",
    question:
      "An injury or illness must be AOE/COE to be covered by workers’ compensation.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. The CHSWC is a state-appointed body that conducts studies and makes recommendations to improve the California workers' compensation and workplace health and safety systems.\n2. Comisión de salud y seguridad y compensación de trabajadores (CHSWC): un organismo designado por el estado que realiza estudios y hace recomendaciones para mejorar los sistemas de compensación de trabajadores y de salud y seguridad en el lugar de trabajo de California.",
    question:
      "AOE / COE: que surge fuera del empleo y en el curso del empleo o es causado por el trabajo de un trabajador y ocurre mientras trabaja. Una lesión o enfermedad debe ser AOE / COE para estar cubierta por la compensación de trabajadores.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. FEHA is a state law that prohibits discrimination against people with disabilities. If you believe you've been discriminated against at work because you're disabled and want more information on your rights under the FEHA, contact the state Department of Fair Employment and Housing at 1-800-884-1684. In some cases, the FEHA provides more protection than the federal Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA).\n2. Ley de empleo y vivienda justos (FEHA): Una ley estatal que prohíbe la discriminación contra personas con discapacidades. Si cree que lo han discriminado en el trabajo porque está discapacitado y desea obtener más información sobre sus derechos en virtud de la FEHA, comuníquese con el Departamento de Equidad de Empleo y Vivienda del estado al 1-800-884-1684. En algunos casos, la FEHA brinda más protección que la Ley Federal de Estadounidenses con Discapacidades (ADA).",
    question: "What is Agreed medical evaluator (AME)?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. A physician selected by the judge (in California) or by the adjuster (in Arizona) to determine the cause of the medical condition, the permanent impairment of the injury, and/or the permanent limitations, if any, that the worker has sustained.\n2. Evaluador médico independiente (IME): Un médico seleccionado por el juez (en California) o por el ajustador (en Arizona) para determinar la causa de la condición médica, el impedimento permanente de la lesión y / o las limitaciones permanentes, si las hubiera, que el trabajador ha sufrido.",
    question:
      "If you have an attorney, an AME is a doctor, your attorney and the insurance company agree to conduct the medical examination that will help resolve your dispute. If you don't have an attorney, you will use a qualified medical evaluator (QME).",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. The term for insurance companies and others that handle your workers' compensation claim. Most claims administrators work for insurance companies or third-party administrators handling claims for employers. Some claims administrators work directly for large employers that handle their own claims. Also called claims examiner or claims adjuster.\n2. Administrador de reclamaciones: El término para las compañías de seguros y otros que manejan su reclamo de compensación para trabajadores. La mayoría de los administradores de reclamos trabajan para compañías de seguros o administradores externos que manejan reclamos para empleadores. Algunos administradores de reclamos trabajan directamente para grandes empleadores que manejan sus propios reclamos. También se llama examinador de reclamos o ajustador de reclamos.",
    question:
      "Evaluador médico acordado (AME): si tiene un abogado, un AME es un médico, su abogado y la compañía de seguros acuerdan realizar el examen médico que ayudará a resolver su disputa. Si no tiene un abogado, utilizará un evaluador médico calificado (QME).",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. Your condition is well stabilized and unlikely to change substantially in the next year, with or without medical treatment. Once you reach MMI, a doctor can assess how much, if any, permanent disability resulted from your work injury.\n2. Mejora médica máxima (MMI): Su condición está bien estabilizada y es poco probable que cambie sustancialmente durante el próximo año, con o sin tratamiento médico. Una vez que llegue a MMI, un médico puede evaluar cuánta discapacidad permanente, si la hubo, resultó de su lesión laboral.",
    question:
      "What is commission on health and safety and workers' compensation (CHSWC)?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. Doctors in California's workers' compensation system are required to provide evidence-based medical treatment. That means they must choose treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. Those treatments are laid out in the medical treatment utilization schedule (MTUS), which contains a set of guidelines that provide details on which treatments are effective for certain injuries, as well as how often the treatment should be given, the extent of the treatment, and for how long, among other things.\n2. Programa de utilización de tratamiento médico (MTUS): Los médicos del sistema de compensación para trabajadores de California deben proporcionar tratamiento médico basado en pruebas. Eso significa que deben elegir tratamientos científicamente probados para curar o aliviar las lesiones y enfermedades relacionadas con el trabajo. Esos tratamientos se establecen en el programa de utilización del tratamiento médico (MTUS), que contiene un conjunto de pautas que brindan detalles sobre qué tratamientos son efectivos para ciertas lesiones, así como la frecuencia con la que se debe administrar el tratamiento, la extensión del tratamiento, y por cuánto tiempo, entre otras cosas.",
    question:
      "The CHSWC is a state-appointed body that conducts studies and makes recommendations to improve the California workers' compensation and workplace health and safety systems.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. A percentage that estimates how much a job injury permanently limits the kinds of work you can do. It is based on your medical condition, date of injury, age when injured, occupation when injured, how much of the disability is caused by your job, and your diminished future earning capacity. It determines the number of weeks you are entitled to permanent disability benefits.\n2. Clasificación de discapacidad permanente (PDR): Un porcentaje que estima cuánto una lesión laboral limita permanentemente los tipos de trabajo que puede realizar. Se basa en su condición médica, la fecha de la lesión, la edad en que se lesionó, la ocupación cuando se lesionó, la cantidad de discapacidad causada por su trabajo y la disminución de su capacidad futura de ingresos. Determina la cantidad de semanas que tiene derecho a recibir beneficios por discapacidad permanente.\n1",
    question:
      "Comisión de salud y seguridad y compensación de trabajadores (CHSWC): un organismo designado por el estado que realiza estudios y hace recomendaciones para mejorar los sistemas de compensación de trabajadores y de salud y seguridad en el lugar de trabajo de California.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. An amount of money you receive because something wasn't done correctly in your claim. Paid by your employer or the insurance company, the penalty amount can be an automatic 10 percent for a delay in one payment to you, or a 25 percent penalty -- up to $10,000 -- for an unreasonable delay.\n2. Multa: Una cantidad de dinero que recibe porque algo no se hizo correctamente en su reclamo. Pagado por su empleador o la compañía de seguros, el monto de la multa puede ser un 10 por ciento automático por una demora en un pago, o una multa del 25 por ciento, hasta $ 10,000, por una demora irrazonable.\n1",
    question: "What is Fair employment and housing act (FEHA)?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. Long-term financial assistance for totally disabled persons. These benefits come from the U.S. Social Security Administration. They are reduced by workers' compensation payments you receive.\n2. Beneficios por discapacidad del Seguro Social: Ayuda económica a largo plazo para personas totalmente discapacitadas. Estos beneficios provienen de la Administración del Seguro Social de EE. UU. Se reducen por los pagos de compensación laboral que recibe.\n1",
    question:
      "FEHA is a state law that prohibits discrimination against people with disabilities. If you believe you've been discriminated against at work because you're disabled and want more information on your rights under the FEHA, contact the state Department of Fair Employment and Housing at 1-800-884-",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. The amount of pain and other symptoms described by an injured worker that a doctor reports as contributing to a worker's permanent disability. Subjective factors are given very little weight under the 2005 rating schedule as the schedule relies mainly on objective measurements.\n2. Factores subjetivos: La cantidad de dolor y otros síntomas descritos por un trabajador lesionado que un médico informa que contribuyen a la discapacidad permanente del trabajador. Los factores subjetivos reciben muy poco peso en el programa de calificación de 2005, ya que el programa se basa principalmente en mediciones objetivas.\n1",
    question:
      "In some cases, the FEHA provides more protection than the federal Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA).",
  },
  {
    answer:
      ": If you have a permanent disability, this is the person or entity that helps you develop a return to work strategy. They evaluate you, provide counseling and help you get ready to work. A VRTWC must have at least an undergraduate degree in any field and three or more years of full-time experience.\n   1. Consejero vocacional y de regreso al trabajo (VRTWC): If you have a permanent disability, this is the person or entity that helps you develop a return to work strategy. They evaluate you, provide counseling and help you get ready to work. A VRTWC must have at least an undergraduate degree in any field and three or more years of full-time experience.\n1",
    question:
      "Ley de empleo y vivienda justos (FEHA): Una ley estatal que prohíbe la discriminación contra personas con discapacidades. Si cree que lo han discriminado en el trabajo porque está discapacitado y desea obtener más información sobre sus derechos en virtud de la FEHA, comuníquese con el Departamento de Equidad de Empleo y Vivienda del estado al 1-800-884-",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. The doctor having overall responsibility for treatment of your work injury or illness. This physician writes medical reports that may affect your benefits. Also called treating physician or treating doctor.\n2. Médico tratante primario (PTP): El médico que tiene la responsabilidad general del tratamiento de su lesión o enfermedad laboral. Este médico redacta informes médicos que pueden afectar sus beneficios. También se llama médico tratante o médico tratante.\n1",
    question:
      "En algunos casos, la FEHA brinda más protección que la Ley Federal de Estadounidenses con Discapacidades (ADA).",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. A settlement in which the parties agree on the terms of an award. It may include future medical treatment. Payment takes place over time. This document is provided to the judge for final review.\n2. Estipulaciones con solicitud de premio (Stips): Un acuerdo en el que las partes acuerdan los términos de un laudo. Puede incluir tratamiento médico futuro. El pago se realiza a lo largo del tiempo. Este documento se le entrega al juez para su revisión final.\n1",
    question: "What is an Independent medical evaluator (IME)?",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. Payments you get if you lose wages because your injury prevents you from doing your usual job while recovering.\n2. Discapacidad temporal (TD o TTD): Pagos que recibe si pierde salario porque su lesión le impide hacer su trabajo habitual mientras se recupera.\n1",
    question:
      "A physician selected by the judge (in California) or by the adjuster (in Arizona) to determine the cause of the medical condition, the permanent impairment of the injury, and/or the permanent limitations, if any, that the worker has sustained.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. Payments you get if you can do some work while recovering, but you earn less than before the injury.\n2. Pagos que recibe si puede trabajar un poco mientras se recupera, pero gana menos que antes de la lesión.\n1",
    question:
      "Evaluador médico independiente (IME): Un médico seleccionado por el juez (en California) o por el ajustador (en Arizona) para determinar la causa de la condición médica, el impedimento permanente de la lesión y / o las limitaciones permanentes, si las hubiera, que el trabajador ha sufrido.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. Payments you get if you cannot work at all while recovering.\n2. Beneficios por discapacidad total temporal (TTD): Pagos que recibe si no puede trabajar en absoluto mientras se recupera.\n1",
    question: "What is a Claims administrator?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. A workers' compensation benefit. If you were injured before 2004 and are permanently unable to do your usual job, and your employer does not offer other work, you qualify for this benefit. It includes job placement counseling to help you find another job. It may also include retraining and a vocational rehabilitation maintenance allowance.\n2. Rehabilitación vocacional (VR): Un beneficio de compensación para trabajadores. Si se lesionó antes de 2004 y no puede realizar su trabajo habitual de forma permanente, y su empleador no le ofrece otro trabajo, califica para este beneficio. Incluye asesoramiento sobre colocación laboral para ayudarlo a encontrar otro trabajo. También puede incluir readiestramiento y un subsidio de mantenimiento para rehabilitación vocacional.\n2",
    question:
      "The term for insurance companies and others that handle your workers' compensation claim. Most claims administrators work for insurance companies or third-party administrators handling claims for employers. Some claims administrators work directly for large employers that handle their own claims. Also called claims examiner or claims adjuster.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. A doctor's description of the work you can and cannot do. Work restrictions help protect you from further injury.\n2. Restricciones laborales: Una descripción del médico del trabajo que puede y no puede hacer. Las restricciones laborales ayudan a protegerlo de más lesiones.",
    question:
      "Administrador de reclamaciones: El término para las compañías de seguros y otros que manejan su reclamo de compensación para trabajadores. La mayoría de los administradores de reclamos trabajan para compañías de seguros o administradores externos que manejan reclamos para empleadores. Algunos administradores de reclamos trabajan directamente para grandes empleadores que manejan sus propios reclamos. También se llama examinador de reclamos o ajustador de reclamos.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. If you have a work-related injury or illness, your employer is required by law to pay for workers' compensation benefits. You could get hurt by:\nOne event at work, such as hurting your back in a fall, getting burned by a chemical that splashes on your skin or getting hurt in a car accident while making deliveries.\n--or--\nRepeated exposures at work, such as hurting your wrist from doing the same motion over and over or losing your hearing because of constant loud noise.",
    question: "What is a Maximal medical improvement (MMI)?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Report the injury to your employer by telling your supervisor right away. If your injury or illness developed over time, report it as soon as you learn or believe it was caused by your job.\nReporting promptly helps prevent problems and delays in receiving benefits, including medical care you may need. If your employer does not learn about your injury within 30 days and this prevents your employer from fully investigating the injury and how you were injured, you could lose your right to receive workers' compensation benefits.\nGet emergency treatment if you need it. Your employer may tell you where to go for treatment. Tell the health care provider who treats you that your injury or illness is job-related.\nFill out a claim form and give it to your employer. Your employer must give or mail you a claim form within one working day after learning about your injury or illness. If your employer doesn't give you the claim form you can download it from the forms page of the DWC website.",
    question:
      "Your condition is well stabilized and unlikely to change substantially in the next year, with or without medical treatment. Once you reach MMI, a doctor can assess how much, if any, permanent disability resulted from your work injury.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Doctors in California's workers' compensation system are required to provide evidence-based medical treatment. That means they must choose treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. Those treatments are laid out in a set of guidelines that provide details on which treatments are effective for certain injuries, as well as how often the treatment should be given (frequency), the extent of the treatment (intensity), and for how long (duration), among other things.",
    question:
      "Mejora médica máxima (MMI): Su condición está bien estabilizada y es poco probable que cambie sustancialmente durante el próximo año, con o sin tratamiento médico. Una vez que llegue a MMI, un médico puede evaluar cuánta discapacidad permanente, si la hubo, resultó de su lesión laboral.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. In California all employers are required to either purchase a workers' compensation insurance policy from a licensed insurer authorized to write policies in California or become self-insured. The DWC does not provide workers' compensation insurance for employers and does not maintain information about employers and their respective insurers. To find out which insurer provides workers' compensation insurance for a specific employer, visit the California Workers' Compensation Coverage website. The roster of self-insured employers can be found on the Self Insurance Plans Web page.",
    question: "What is a Medical treatment utilization schedule (MTUS)?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Before an injury or illness occurs, your employer must:\n* Obtain workers' compensation insurance or qualify to become self-insured\n* When hiring a new employee, provide a workers' compensation pamphlet explaining the employee's rights and responsibilities\n* Post the workers' compensation poster in a place where all employees can see it.\nAfter an injury or illness occurs, your employer must:\n* Provide a workers' compensation claim form to you within one working day a work-related injury or illness is reported\n* Return a completed copy of the claim form to you within one working day of receipt\n* Forward the claim form, along with the employer's report of occupational injury or illness, to the claims administrator within one working day of receipt\n* Within one day of receiving your claim, authorize up to $10,000 in appropriate medical treatment\n* Provide transitional work (light duty) whenever appropriate\n* If you are the victim of a crime that happened at work, the employer must give notice of workers' compensation eligibility within one working day of the crime.",
    question:
      "Doctors in California's workers' compensation system are required to provide evidence-based medical treatment. That means they must choose treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. Those treatments are laid out in the medical treatment utilization schedule (MTUS), which contains a set of guidelines that provide details on which treatments are effective for certain injuries, as well as how often the treatment should be given, the extent of the treatment, and for how long, among other things.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Failing to have workers' compensation coverage is a criminal offense a misdemeanor punishable by either a fine of up to $10,000 or imprisonment in the county jail for up to one year, or both. Additionally, the state issues penalties of up to $100,000 against illegally uninsured employers.",
    question:
      "Programa de utilización de tratamiento médico (MTUS): Los médicos del sistema de compensación para trabajadores de California deben proporcionar tratamiento médico basado en pruebas. Eso significa que deben elegir tratamientos científicamente probados para curar o aliviar las lesiones y enfermedades relacionadas con el trabajo. Esos tratamientos se establecen en el programa de utilización del tratamiento médico (MTUS), que contiene un conjunto de pautas que brindan detalles sobre qué tratamientos son efectivos para ciertas lesiones, así como la frecuencia con la que se debe administrar el tratamiento, la extensión del tratamiento, y por cuánto tiempo, entre otras cosas.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1. No. Workers' compensation insurance is part of the cost of doing business. An employer cannot ask you to help pay for the insurance premium.",
    question: "What is a Permanent disability rating (PDR)?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Yes. If your date of injury is in 2004 or later, you are limited to a total of 24 chiropractic visits, 24 physical therapy visits, and 24 occupational therapy visits, unless the claims administrator authorizes additional visits or you have recently had surgery and need postsurgical physical medicine.",
    question:
      "A percentage that estimates how much a job injury permanently limits the kinds of work you can do. It is based on your medical condition, date of injury, age when injured, occupation when injured, how much of the disability is caused by your job, and your diminished future earning capacity. It determines the number of weeks you are entitled to permanent disability benefits.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. The claims administrator is required to authorize medical treatment within one working day after you file a claim form with your employer, even while your claim is being investigated. The total cost of the treatment provided while your claim is being investigated is limited to $10,000. If the claims administrator does not authorize treatment right away, speak with your supervisor, someone else in management or the claims administrator about the law requiring immediate medical treatment. Ask for treatment to be authorized now, while waiting for a decision on your claim.\n1",
    question:
      "Clasificación de discapacidad permanente (PDR): Un porcentaje que estima cuánto una lesión laboral limita permanentemente los tipos de trabajo que puede realizar. Se basa en su condición médica, la fecha de la lesión, la edad en que se lesionó, la ocupación cuando se lesionó, la cantidad de discapacidad causada por su trabajo y la disminución de su capacidad futura de ingresos. Determina la cantidad de semanas que tiene derecho a recibir beneficios por discapacidad permanente.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. You most likely will not have to pay. This is a problem your doctor and the claims administrator need to work out.\n1",
    question: "What is a Penalty?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. For as long as it's medically necessary. However, some treatments are limited by law and the medical treatment you receive must be evidence-based.\nThe MTUS lays out treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. It also deals with how often the treatment is given and for how long, among other things.\nIf the treatment your doctor wants to provide goes beyond what is recommended by the MTUS, your doctor must use other evidence to show the treatment is necessary and will be effective.\nAdditionally, your doctor's treatment plan may be reviewed by a third party hired by the claims administrator. This process is called utilization review (UR). All claims administrators are required by law to have a UR program. They use UR to decide whether or not to approve treatment recommended by your doctor.\n1",
    question:
      "An amount of money you receive because something wasn't done correctly in your claim. Paid by your employer or the insurance company, the penalty amount can be an automatic 10 percent for a delay in one payment to you, or a 25 percent penalty -- up to $10,000 -- for an unreasonable delay.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. No. The 24 visit cap does not apply to injuries that occurred before Jan. 1, 2004. Also, the cap does not apply if your employer authorizes additional visits in writing. Additionally, the cap does not apply to visits for certain postsurgical physical medicine and rehabilitation services.\n1",
    question:
      "Multa: Una cantidad de dinero que recibe porque algo no se hizo correctamente en su reclamo. Pagado por su empleador o la compañía de seguros, el monto de la multa puede ser un 10 por ciento automático por una demora en un pago, o una multa del 25 por ciento, hasta $ 10,000, por una demora irrazonable.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. As a general rule, TD pays two-thirds of the gross (pre-tax) wages you lose while you are recovering from a job injury. However, you cannot receive more than the maximum weekly amount set by law. Your wages are figured out by using all forms of income you receive from work: wages, food, lodging, tips, commissions, overtime and bonuses. Wages can also include earnings from work you did at other jobs at the time you were injured. Give proof of these earnings to the claims administrator. The claims administrator will consider all forms of income when calculating your TD benefits. The minimum and maximum rates are adjusted annually.\n1",
    question: "What is Social Security disability benefits?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. No. You don't pay federal, state or local income tax on TD benefits. Also you don't pay Social Security, taxes, union dues or retirement fund contributions.\n1",
    question:
      "Long-term financial assistance for totally disabled persons. These benefits come from the U.S. Social Security Administration. They are reduced by workers' compensation payments you receive.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Most workers fully recover from job injuries but some continue to have medical problems. Permanent disability (PD) is any lasting disability that results in a reduced earning capacity after maximum medical improvement is reached. If your injury or illness results in PD you are entitled to PD benefits, even if you are able to go back to work.\nPD benefits are limited. If you lose income, PD benefits may not cover all the income lost. If you experience losses unrelated to your ability to work, PD benefits may not cover those losses. See the DWC fact sheet on PD for more information.\n\n\n1",
    question:
      "Beneficios por discapacidad del Seguro Social: Ayuda económica a largo plazo para personas totalmente discapacitadas. Estos beneficios provienen de la Administración del Seguro Social de EE. UU. Se reducen por los pagos de compensación laboral que recibe.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Returning to work safely and promptly can help in your recovery. It can also help you avoid financial\nlosses from being off work. After you are hurt on the job, several people will work with you to decide when you will return to work and what work you will do. These people include:\n* Your treating doctor\n* Managers who represent your employer\n* The claims administrator handling your claim for your employer.\nSometimes doctors and claims administrators do not fully understand your job or other jobs that could be assigned to you. That's why it is important that everyone stay in close contact throughout the process. You (and your attorney if you have one) should actively communicate with your treating doctor, your employer and the claims administrator about:\n* The work you did before you were injured\n* Your medical condition and the kinds of work you can do now\n* The kinds of work your employer could make available to you.\n\n\n1",
    question: "What are Subjective factors?:",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. Soon after your injury, the treating doctor examines you and sends a report to the claims administrator about your medical condition. If the treating doctor says you are able to work, he or she should describe:\n* Clear and specific limits, if any, on your job tasks while recovering. These are called work restrictions. They are intended to protect you from further injury (example: no work that requires repetitive bending or stooping)\n* Changes needed, if any, in your schedule, assignments, equipment or other working conditions while recovering (example: provide headset to avoid awkward positions of the head and neck)\n* If the treating doctor reports that you cannot work at all while recovering you cannot be required to work.\n\n\n1",
    question:
      "The amount of pain and other symptoms described by an injured worker that a doctor reports as contributing to a worker's permanent disability. Subjective factors are given very little weight under the 2005 rating schedule as the schedule relies mainly on objective measurements.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. The state's experience and extensive studies have shown that the longer you stay off work the less likely you are to go back, and that leads to more wage loss and a lower quality of life. PD benefits will never make up for the money you lose by not returning to work, so these provisions were put in place to get you back to your job as soon as medically possible.\n1",
    question:
      "Factores subjetivos: La cantidad de dolor y otros síntomas descritos por un trabajador lesionado que un médico informa que contribuyen a la discapacidad permanente del trabajador. Los factores subjetivos reciben muy poco peso en el programa de calificación de 2005, ya que el programa se basa principalmente en mediciones objetivas.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "A. If the claims administrator's letter says your employer is offering you work, the job must meet the work restrictions in the doctor's report. The offer could involve:\n* Regular work: Your old job, for a period of at least 12 months, paying the same wages and benefits as paid at the time of an injury and located within a reasonable commuting distance of where you lived at the time of your injury\n* Modified work: Your old job, with some changes that allow you do to it. If your doctor says you will not be able to return to the job you had at the time of injury, your employer is encouraged to offer you modified work instead of supplemental job displacement benefits (SJDB). The alternative work must meet your work restrictions, last at least 12 months, pay at least 85 percent of the wages and benefits you were paid at the time you were injured and be within a reasonable commuting distance of where you lived at the time of injury\n* Alternative work: A new job with your employer. If your doctor says you will not be able to return to the job you had at the time of injury, your employer is encouraged to offer you alternative work instead of SJDB. The alternative work must meet your work restrictions, last at least 12 months, pay at least 85 percent of the wages and benefits you were paid at the time you were injured, and be within a reasonable commuting distance of where you lived at the time of injury.\nIf your employer offers you modified or alternative work:\n* You may have only 30 days to accept the offer. If you don't respond within 30 days, your employer could withdraw the offer\n* If you fail to respond to the offer of modified or alternative work within 30 days or reject the job offer, you will probably not be entitled to supplemental job displacement benefits.\n\n\n2",
    question:
      "What is a Vocational & return to work counselor (VRTWC)?: If you have a permanent disability, this is the person or entity that helps you develop a return to work strategy. They evaluate you, provide counseling and help you get ready to work. A VRTWC must have at least an undergraduate degree in any field and three or more years of full-time experience.",
  },
  {
    answer:
      "1.  An injury or illness must be AOE/COE to be covered by workers’ compensation.\n2. AOE / COE: que surge fuera del empleo y en el curso del empleo o es causado por el trabajo de un trabajador y ocurre mientras trabaja. Una lesión o enfermedad debe ser AOE / COE para estar cubierta por la compensación de trabajadores.\n2. What is Agreed medical evaluator (AME)?: \n   1. If you have an attorney, an AME is a doctor, your attorney and the insurance company agree to conduct the medical examination that will help resolve your dispute. If you don't have an attorney, you will use a qualified medical evaluator (QME).\n2. Evaluador médico acordado (AME): si tiene un abogado, un AME es un médico, su abogado y la compañía de seguros acuerdan realizar el examen médico que ayudará a resolver su disputa. Si no tiene un abogado, utilizará un evaluador médico calificado (QME).\n3. What is commission on health and safety and workers' compensation (CHSWC)?: \n   1. The CHSWC is a state-appointed body that conducts studies and makes recommendations to improve the California workers' compensation and workplace health and safety systems.\n2. Comisión de salud y seguridad y compensación de trabajadores (CHSWC): un organismo designado por el estado que realiza estudios y hace recomendaciones para mejorar los sistemas de compensación de trabajadores y de salud y seguridad en el lugar de trabajo de California.\n\n\n4. What is Fair employment and housing act (FEHA)?: \n   1. FEHA is a state law that prohibits discrimination against people with disabilities. If you believe you've been discriminated against at work because you're disabled and want more information on your rights under the FEHA, contact the state Department of Fair Employment and Housing at 1-800-884-1684. In some cases, the FEHA provides more protection than the federal Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA).\n2. Ley de empleo y vivienda justos (FEHA): Una ley estatal que prohíbe la discriminación contra personas con discapacidades. Si cree que lo han discriminado en el trabajo porque está discapacitado y desea obtener más información sobre sus derechos en virtud de la FEHA, comuníquese con el Departamento de Equidad de Empleo y Vivienda del estado al 1-800-884-1684. En algunos casos, la FEHA brinda más protección que la Ley Federal de Estadounidenses con Discapacidades (ADA).\n5. What is an Independent medical evaluator (IME)? \n   1. A physician selected by the judge (in California) or by the adjuster (in Arizona) to determine the cause of the medical condition, the permanent impairment of the injury, and/or the permanent limitations, if any, that the worker has sustained.\n2. Evaluador médico independiente (IME): Un médico seleccionado por el juez (en California) o por el ajustador (en Arizona) para determinar la causa de la condición médica, el impedimento permanente de la lesión y / o las limitaciones permanentes, si las hubiera, que el trabajador ha sufrido.\n6. What is a Claims administrator?: \n   1. The term for insurance companies and others that handle your workers' compensation claim. Most claims administrators work for insurance companies or third-party administrators handling claims for employers. Some claims administrators work directly for large employers that handle their own claims. Also called claims examiner or claims adjuster.\n2. Administrador de reclamaciones: El término para las compañías de seguros y otros que manejan su reclamo de compensación para trabajadores. La mayoría de los administradores de reclamos trabajan para compañías de seguros o administradores externos que manejan reclamos para empleadores. Algunos administradores de reclamos trabajan directamente para grandes empleadores que manejan sus propios reclamos. También se llama examinador de reclamos o ajustador de reclamos.\n7. What is a Maximal medical improvement (MMI)?: \n   1. Your condition is well stabilized and unlikely to change substantially in the next year, with or without medical treatment. Once you reach MMI, a doctor can assess how much, if any, permanent disability resulted from your work injury.\n2. Mejora médica máxima (MMI): Su condición está bien estabilizada y es poco probable que cambie sustancialmente durante el próximo año, con o sin tratamiento médico. Una vez que llegue a MMI, un médico puede evaluar cuánta discapacidad permanente, si la hubo, resultó de su lesión laboral.\n8. What is a Medical treatment utilization schedule (MTUS)?: \n   1. Doctors in California's workers' compensation system are required to provide evidence-based medical treatment. That means they must choose treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. Those treatments are laid out in the medical treatment utilization schedule (MTUS), which contains a set of guidelines that provide details on which treatments are effective for certain injuries, as well as how often the treatment should be given, the extent of the treatment, and for how long, among other things.\n2. Programa de utilización de tratamiento médico (MTUS): Los médicos del sistema de compensación para trabajadores de California deben proporcionar tratamiento médico basado en pruebas. Eso significa que deben elegir tratamientos científicamente probados para curar o aliviar las lesiones y enfermedades relacionadas con el trabajo. Esos tratamientos se establecen en el programa de utilización del tratamiento médico (MTUS), que contiene un conjunto de pautas que brindan detalles sobre qué tratamientos son efectivos para ciertas lesiones, así como la frecuencia con la que se debe administrar el tratamiento, la extensión del tratamiento, y por cuánto tiempo, entre otras cosas.\n9. What is a Permanent disability rating (PDR)?: \n   1. A percentage that estimates how much a job injury permanently limits the kinds of work you can do. It is based on your medical condition, date of injury, age when injured, occupation when injured, how much of the disability is caused by your job, and your diminished future earning capacity. It determines the number of weeks you are entitled to permanent disability benefits.\n2. Clasificación de discapacidad permanente (PDR): Un porcentaje que estima cuánto una lesión laboral limita permanentemente los tipos de trabajo que puede realizar. Se basa en su condición médica, la fecha de la lesión, la edad en que se lesionó, la ocupación cuando se lesionó, la cantidad de discapacidad causada por su trabajo y la disminución de su capacidad futura de ingresos. Determina la cantidad de semanas que tiene derecho a recibir beneficios por discapacidad permanente.\n10. What is a Penalty?: \n   1. An amount of money you receive because something wasn't done correctly in your claim. Paid by your employer or the insurance company, the penalty amount can be an automatic 10 percent for a delay in one payment to you, or a 25 percent penalty -- up to $10,000 -- for an unreasonable delay.\n2. Multa: Una cantidad de dinero que recibe porque algo no se hizo correctamente en su reclamo. Pagado por su empleador o la compañía de seguros, el monto de la multa puede ser un 10 por ciento automático por una demora en un pago, o una multa del 25 por ciento, hasta $ 10,000, por una demora irrazonable.\n11. What is Social Security disability benefits?: \n   1. Long-term financial assistance for totally disabled persons. These benefits come from the U.S. Social Security Administration. They are reduced by workers' compensation payments you receive.\n2. Beneficios por discapacidad del Seguro Social: Ayuda económica a largo plazo para personas totalmente discapacitadas. Estos beneficios provienen de la Administración del Seguro Social de EE. UU. Se reducen por los pagos de compensación laboral que recibe.\n12. What are Subjective factors?: \n   1. The amount of pain and other symptoms described by an injured worker that a doctor reports as contributing to a worker's permanent disability. Subjective factors are given very little weight under the 2005 rating schedule as the schedule relies mainly on objective measurements.\n2. Factores subjetivos: La cantidad de dolor y otros síntomas descritos por un trabajador lesionado que un médico informa que contribuyen a la discapacidad permanente del trabajador. Los factores subjetivos reciben muy poco peso en el programa de calificación de 2005, ya que el programa se basa principalmente en mediciones objetivas.\n13. What is a Vocational & return to work counselor (VRTWC)?: If you have a permanent disability, this is the person or entity that helps you develop a return to work strategy. They evaluate you, provide counseling and help you get ready to work. A VRTWC must have at least an undergraduate degree in any field and three or more years of full-time experience.\n   1. Consejero vocacional y de regreso al trabajo (VRTWC): If you have a permanent disability, this is the person or entity that helps you develop a return to work strategy. They evaluate you, provide counseling and help you get ready to work. A VRTWC must have at least an undergraduate degree in any field and three or more years of full-time experience.\n14. What is a Primary treating physician (PTP)?: \n   1. The doctor having overall responsibility for treatment of your work injury or illness. This physician writes medical reports that may affect your benefits. Also called treating physician or treating doctor.\n2. Médico tratante primario (PTP): El médico que tiene la responsabilidad general del tratamiento de su lesión o enfermedad laboral. Este médico redacta informes médicos que pueden afectar sus beneficios. También se llama médico tratante o médico tratante.\n15. What is are Stipulations with request for award (Stips)?: \n   1. A settlement in which the parties agree on the terms of an award. It may include future medical treatment. Payment takes place over time. This document is provided to the judge for final review.\n2. Estipulaciones con solicitud de premio (Stips): Un acuerdo en el que las partes acuerdan los términos de un laudo. Puede incluir tratamiento médico futuro. El pago se realiza a lo largo del tiempo. Este documento se le entrega al juez para su revisión final.\n16. What are Temporary disability (TD or TTD)?: \n   1. Payments you get if you lose wages because your injury prevents you from doing your usual job while recovering.\n2. Discapacidad temporal (TD o TTD): Pagos que recibe si pierde salario porque su lesión le impide hacer su trabajo habitual mientras se recupera.\n17. What are Temporary partial disability (TPD) benefits?: \n   1. Payments you get if you can do some work while recovering, but you earn less than before the injury.\n2. Pagos que recibe si puede trabajar un poco mientras se recupera, pero gana menos que antes de la lesión.\n18. What are Temporary total disability (TTD) benefits?: \n   1. Payments you get if you cannot work at all while recovering.\n2. Beneficios por discapacidad total temporal (TTD): Pagos que recibe si no puede trabajar en absoluto mientras se recupera.\n19. What is Vocational rehabilitation (VR)?: \n   1. A workers' compensation benefit. If you were injured before 2004 and are permanently unable to do your usual job, and your employer does not offer other work, you qualify for this benefit. It includes job placement counseling to help you find another job. It may also include retraining and a vocational rehabilitation maintenance allowance.\n2. Rehabilitación vocacional (VR): Un beneficio de compensación para trabajadores. Si se lesionó antes de 2004 y no puede realizar su trabajo habitual de forma permanente, y su empleador no le ofrece otro trabajo, califica para este beneficio. Incluye asesoramiento sobre colocación laboral para ayudarlo a encontrar otro trabajo. También puede incluir readiestramiento y un subsidio de mantenimiento para rehabilitación vocacional.\n20. What are Work restrictions?: \n   1. A doctor's description of the work you can and cannot do. Work restrictions help protect you from further injury.\n2. Restricciones laborales: Una descripción del médico del trabajo que puede y no puede hacer. Las restricciones laborales ayudan a protegerlo de más lesiones.\n\n\n1. What is workers' compensation?\n\n\nA. If you have a work-related injury or illness, your employer is required by law to pay for workers' compensation benefits. You could get hurt by:\nOne event at work, such as hurting your back in a fall, getting burned by a chemical that splashes on your skin or getting hurt in a car accident while making deliveries.\n--or--\nRepeated exposures at work, such as hurting your wrist from doing the same motion over and over or losing your hearing because of constant loud noise.\n\n\n2. What should I do if I have a job injury?\nA. Report the injury to your employer by telling your supervisor right away. If your injury or illness developed over time, report it as soon as you learn or believe it was caused by your job.\nReporting promptly helps prevent problems and delays in receiving benefits, including medical care you may need. If your employer does not learn about your injury within 30 days and this prevents your employer from fully investigating the injury and how you were injured, you could lose your right to receive workers' compensation benefits.\nGet emergency treatment if you need it. Your employer may tell you where to go for treatment. Tell the health care provider who treats you that your injury or illness is job-related.\nFill out a claim form and give it to your employer. Your employer must give or mail you a claim form within one working day after learning about your injury or illness. If your employer doesn't give you the claim form you can download it from the forms page of the DWC website.\n3. What kind of medical care will I receive for my injury?\nA. Doctors in California's workers' compensation system are required to provide evidence-based medical treatment. That means they must choose treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. Those treatments are laid out in a set of guidelines that provide details on which treatments are effective for certain injuries, as well as how often the treatment should be given (frequency), the extent of the treatment (intensity), and for how long (duration), among other things.\n4. How can I find out who provides workers' compensation coverage for my employer or another business in California?\nA. In California all employers are required to either purchase a workers' compensation insurance policy from a licensed insurer authorized to write policies in California or become self-insured. The DWC does not provide workers' compensation insurance for employers and does not maintain information about employers and their respective insurers. To find out which insurer provides workers' compensation insurance for a specific employer, visit the California Workers' Compensation Coverage website. The roster of self-insured employers can be found on the Self Insurance Plans Web page.\n\n\n5. What are my employer's responsibilities under workers' compensation laws?\nA. Before an injury or illness occurs, your employer must:\n* Obtain workers' compensation insurance or qualify to become self-insured\n* When hiring a new employee, provide a workers' compensation pamphlet explaining the employee's rights and responsibilities\n* Post the workers' compensation poster in a place where all employees can see it.\nAfter an injury or illness occurs, your employer must:\n* Provide a workers' compensation claim form to you within one working day a work-related injury or illness is reported\n* Return a completed copy of the claim form to you within one working day of receipt\n* Forward the claim form, along with the employer's report of occupational injury or illness, to the claims administrator within one working day of receipt\n* Within one day of receiving your claim, authorize up to $10,000 in appropriate medical treatment\n* Provide transitional work (light duty) whenever appropriate\n* If you are the victim of a crime that happened at work, the employer must give notice of workers' compensation eligibility within one working day of the crime.\n\n\n6. What happens if my employer is uninsured and I'm hurt on the job?\nA. Failing to have workers' compensation coverage is a criminal offense a misdemeanor punishable by either a fine of up to $10,000 or imprisonment in the county jail for up to one year, or both. Additionally, the state issues penalties of up to $100,000 against illegally uninsured employers.\n\n\n7. Can my employer take part of my check to pay for workers' compensation insurance?\n   1. No. Workers' compensation insurance is part of the cost of doing business. An employer cannot ask you to help pay for the insurance premium.\n8. Are there limits on certain kinds of treatment?\nA. Yes. If your date of injury is in 2004 or later, you are limited to a total of 24 chiropractic visits, 24 physical therapy visits, and 24 occupational therapy visits, unless the claims administrator authorizes additional visits or you have recently had surgery and need postsurgical physical medicine.\n9. The claims administrator hasn't accepted or denied my claim yet, but I need medical care for my injury now. What can I do?\nA. The claims administrator is required to authorize medical treatment within one working day after you file a claim form with your employer, even while your claim is being investigated. The total cost of the treatment provided while your claim is being investigated is limited to $10,000. If the claims administrator does not authorize treatment right away, speak with your supervisor, someone else in management or the claims administrator about the law requiring immediate medical treatment. Ask for treatment to be authorized now, while waiting for a decision on your claim.\n10.  What happens if I was treated and the claims administrator won't pay for it? Do I have to pay?\nA. You most likely will not have to pay. This is a problem your doctor and the claims administrator need to work out.\n11.  How long can I continue to receive treatment?\nA. For as long as it's medically necessary. However, some treatments are limited by law and the medical treatment you receive must be evidence-based.\nThe MTUS lays out treatments scientifically proven to cure or relieve work-related injuries and illnesses. It also deals with how often the treatment is given and for how long, among other things.\nIf the treatment your doctor wants to provide goes beyond what is recommended by the MTUS, your doctor must use other evidence to show the treatment is necessary and will be effective.\nAdditionally, your doctor's treatment plan may be reviewed by a third party hired by the claims administrator. This process is called utilization review (UR). All claims administrators are required by law to have a UR program. They use UR to decide whether or not to approve treatment recommended by your doctor.\n12. Does the 24 visit cap on chiropractic visits apply to all cases?\nA. No. The 24 visit cap does not apply to injuries that occurred before Jan. 1, 2004. Also, the cap does not apply if your employer authorizes additional visits in writing. Additionally, the cap does not apply to visits for certain postsurgical physical medicine and rehabilitation services.\n13. How much will I receive in TD payments?\nA. As a general rule, TD pays two-thirds of the gross (pre-tax) wages you lose while you are recovering from a job injury. However, you cannot receive more than the maximum weekly amount set by law. Your wages are figured out by using all forms of income you receive from work: wages, food, lodging, tips, commissions, overtime and bonuses. Wages can also include earnings from work you did at other jobs at the time you were injured. Give proof of these earnings to the claims administrator. The claims administrator will consider all forms of income when calculating your TD benefits. The minimum and maximum rates are adjusted annually.\n14.  Are TD benefits taxable?\nA. No. You don't pay federal, state or local income tax on TD benefits. Also you don't pay Social Security, taxes, union dues or retirement fund contributions.\n15.  What are permanent disability benefits?\nA. Most workers fully recover from job injuries but some continue to have medical problems. Permanent disability (PD) is any lasting disability that results in a reduced earning capacity after maximum medical improvement is reached. If your injury or illness results in PD you are entitled to PD benefits, even if you are able to go back to work.\nPD benefits are limited. If you lose income, PD benefits may not cover all the income lost. If you experience losses unrelated to your ability to work, PD benefits may not cover those losses. See the DWC fact sheet on PD for more information.\n\n\n16.  How is my ability to return to work determined?\nA. Returning to work safely and promptly can help in your recovery. It can also help you avoid financial\nlosses from being off work. After you are hurt on the job, several people will work with you to decide when you will return to work and what work you will do. These people include:\n* Your treating doctor\n* Managers who represent your employer\n* The claims administrator handling your claim for your employer.\nSometimes doctors and claims administrators do not fully understand your job or other jobs that could be assigned to you. That's why it is important that everyone stay in close contact throughout the process. You (and your attorney if you have one) should actively communicate with your treating doctor, your employer and the claims administrator about:\n* The work you did before you were injured\n* Your medical condition and the kinds of work you can do now\n* The kinds of work your employer could make available to you.\n\n\n17.  Can I work while I am recovering?\nA. Soon after your injury, the treating doctor examines you and sends a report to the claims administrator about your medical condition. If the treating doctor says you are able to work, he or she should describe:\n* Clear and specific limits, if any, on your job tasks while recovering. These are called work restrictions. They are intended to protect you from further injury (example: no work that requires repetitive bending or stooping)\n* Changes needed, if any, in your schedule, assignments, equipment or other working conditions while recovering (example: provide headset to avoid awkward positions of the head and neck)\n* If the treating doctor reports that you cannot work at all while recovering you cannot be required to work.\n\n\n18. Why are my PD disability benefits affected by the return to work offer?\nA. The state's experience and extensive studies have shown that the longer you stay off work the less likely you are to go back, and that leads to more wage loss and a lower quality of life. PD benefits will never make up for the money you lose by not returning to work, so these provisions were put in place to get you back to your job as soon as medically possible.\n19.  What if my employer offers me work?\nA. If the claims administrator's letter says your employer is offering you work, the job must meet the work restrictions in the doctor's report. The offer could involve:\n* Regular work: Your old job, for a period of at least 12 months, paying the same wages and benefits as paid at the time of an injury and located within a reasonable commuting distance of where you lived at the time of your injury\n* Modified work: Your old job, with some changes that allow you do to it. If your doctor says you will not be able to return to the job you had at the time of injury, your employer is encouraged to offer you modified work instead of supplemental job displacement benefits (SJDB). The alternative work must meet your work restrictions, last at least 12 months, pay at least 85 percent of the wages and benefits you were paid at the time you were injured and be within a reasonable commuting distance of where you lived at the time of injury\n* Alternative work: A new job with your employer. If your doctor says you will not be able to return to the job you had at the time of injury, your employer is encouraged to offer you alternative work instead of SJDB. The alternative work must meet your work restrictions, last at least 12 months, pay at least 85 percent of the wages and benefits you were paid at the time you were injured, and be within a reasonable commuting distance of where you lived at the time of injury.\nIf your employer offers you modified or alternative work:\n* You may have only 30 days to accept the offer. If you don't respond within 30 days, your employer could withdraw the offer\n* If you fail to respond to the offer of modified or alternative work within 30 days or reject the job offer, you will probably not be entitled to supplemental job displacement benefits.\n\n\n20. Besides workers' compensation benefits, can I get any other financial assistance?\nA. Other benefits may be available. These include:\n* Benefits paid by the state and federal governments such as State Disability Insurance (SDI), unemployment insurance, and Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) payments\n* Benefits offered by employers and unions, such as sick leave, group health insurance, long term disability (LTD) and salary continuation plans\n* Payments if your injury was caused by someone other than your employer.",
    question:
      "Consejero vocacional y de regreso al trabajo (VRTWC): If you have a permanent disability, this is the person or entity that helps you develop a return to work strategy. They evaluate you, provide counseling and help you get ready to work. A VRTWC must have at least an undergraduate degree in any field and three or more years of full-time experience.",
  },
];
